{"questions": [{"question": "Which one is the capital of Morocco?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Rabat", "incorrectAnswers": ["Casablanca", "Fes", "Marrakech"]}, {"question": "The four main divisions of philosophy are metaphysics, epistomology, axiology and ...", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Logic", "incorrectAnswers": ["Bioethics", "Aesthetics", "Categorical logic"]}, {"question": "Which river flows through Egypt?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Nile", "incorrectAnswers": ["Amazon", "Volga", "Rhine"]}, {"question": "What is the brain of the computer?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "CPU", "incorrectAnswers": ["Monitor", "Keyboard", "Hard drive"]}, {"question": "What does RAM stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Random access memory", "incorrectAnswers": ["Read access memory", "Run access memory", "Random allocation memory"]}, {"question": "Which was the name of Aphrodite Child's first album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "End Of The World", "incorrectAnswers": ["It's Five O'Clock", "666", "Reflection"]}, {"question": "What year did Yes release their debut album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "1969", "incorrectAnswers": ["1974", "1973", "1971"]}, {"question": "Which letter is silent in the word 'solemn'?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "n", "incorrectAnswers": ["m", "s", "l"]}, {"question": "We are at about 4000 BC, looking for the original speakers of Indo-European. What area would be the best place to look?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Eurasian steppes", "incorrectAnswers": ["Anatolian plateau", "Iberian Peninsula", "Northern India"]}, {"question": "Which of these former languages in Italy is not considered to be an Indo-European language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Etruscan", "incorrectAnswers": ["South Picene", "Oscan", "Umbrian"]}, {"question": "Which of those is not an album by Premiata Forneria Marconi?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Io sono nato libero", "incorrectAnswers": ["Per un amico", "Storia di un minuto", "L'isola di niente"]}, {"question": "In which modern-day country did the Inca Empire exist?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Peru", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mexico", "Venezuela", "Guatemala"]}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Catch-22' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Joseph Heller", "incorrectAnswers": ["Vladimir Nabokov", "Cassandra Clare", "Kurt Vonnegut"]}, {"question": "Which British band released the album 'Parachutes' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Coldplay", "incorrectAnswers": ["Oasis", "Pulp", "Radiohead"]}, {"question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Honduras", "incorrectAnswers": ["El Salvador", "Guatemala", "Nicaragua"]}, {"question": "When was the partition between India and Pakistan?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "1947", "incorrectAnswers": ["1763", "1891", "1999"]}, {"question": "Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Who", "incorrectAnswers": ["Led Zeppelin", "Deep Purple", "The Kinks"]}, {"question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called _______ .", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Benelux", "incorrectAnswers": ["Benengium", "Nethiumberg", "Luxelneth"]}, {"question": "What is the capital of Chad?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "N'djamena", "incorrectAnswers": ["Yaounde", "Luanda", "Bangui"]}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'Man is born free, but is everywhere in chains' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Jean-Jacques Rousseau", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "Baruch de Spinoza", "Jean-Paul Sartre"]}, {"question": "Who wrote \"The Great Gatsby\" ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ray Bradbury", "Harper Lee", "Joseph Heller"]}, {"question": "What did British Honduras change its name to in 1973?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Belize", "incorrectAnswers": ["Barbados", "Jamaica", "Guatemala"]}, {"question": "Which US state is divided into two parts by a large lake?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Michigan", "incorrectAnswers": ["Wisconsin", "Minnesota", "Ohio"]}, {"question": "Which English heavy metal band released the album 'The Number of the Beast' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Iron Maiden", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mot\u00f6rhead", "Black Sabbath", "Judas Priest"]}, {"question": "Which is a measure of computer performance in intensive calculations?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "FLOPS", "incorrectAnswers": ["POSIX", "GIGO", "ECOS"]}, {"question": "When creating a website, what is one of the things, CSS allows you to do?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Adjust font size", "incorrectAnswers": ["Copy to clipboard", "Attach event listener", "Database queries"]}, {"question": "In which sequence get elements closer to each other as it progresses?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Cauchy sequence", "incorrectAnswers": ["Arithmetic sequence", "Mersenne primes", "Fibonacci sequence"]}, {"question": "What is the range of this dataset: {7,9,17,6,8}?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "11", "incorrectAnswers": ["6", "8", "9"]}, {"question": "What is the second note of the major G scale?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "A", "incorrectAnswers": ["E", "C", "F#"]}, {"question": "What is a common method for training artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Backpropagation", "incorrectAnswers": ["Vertex enumeration", "Hessenberg expansion", "Gauss-Jordan elimination"]}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'The Lord of the Rings'?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "J. R. R. Tolkien", "incorrectAnswers": ["Philip Pullman", "G. K. Chesterton", "C. S. Lewis"]}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'One cannot step twice in the same river' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Heraclitus", "incorrectAnswers": ["Denis Diderot", "Baruch de Spinoza", "Ludwig Wittgenstein"]}, {"question": "If a mathematical function is both -injective and surjective-, it is...", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "bijective", "incorrectAnswers": ["superjective", "intersubjective", "perijective"]}, {"question": "The Occitan language is spoken in certain parts of Southern ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "France", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mexico", "Russia", "Iran"]}, {"question": "What transforms high level source code into assembly or machine code?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "compiler", "incorrectAnswers": ["abstracter", "embedder", "decoder"]}, {"question": "What is the second largest state in the USA?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Texas", "incorrectAnswers": ["California", "Florida", "Oregon"]}, {"question": "Which album cover did Andy Warhol design for the Rolling Stones?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Sticky Fingers", "incorrectAnswers": ["Beggars Banquet", "Exile on Main St", "Let it Bleed"]}, {"question": "Which of these countries border Russia?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "North Korea", "incorrectAnswers": ["Kyrgyzstan", "Uzbekistan", "Tajikistan"]}, {"question": "A technique in the construction of large language models is RLHF, which stands for Reinforcement Learning from ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Human Feedback", "incorrectAnswers": ["Heuristic Factorials", "Hypergeometric Faces", "Hidden Frequencies"]}, {"question": "Euler's number (e) is the base of ... ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Natural logarithms", "incorrectAnswers": ["Complex logarithms", "Imaginary logarithms", "Rational logarithms"]}, {"question": "Which method can be used to predict the probability of one out of two possible outcomes, based on one or more variables?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Logistic regression", "incorrectAnswers": ["Linear regression", "Chi-squared test", "Dynamic scaling"]}, {"question": "The language 'Egyptian Arabic' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Afroasiatic", "incorrectAnswers": ["Austronesian", "Dravidian", "Uralic"]}, {"question": "Which city is the most populated in South Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Johannesburg", "incorrectAnswers": ["Durban", "Pretoria", "Cape Town"]}, {"question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2003?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mystic River", "Lost in Translation", "Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World"]}, {"question": "Which song was originally recorded by Joni Mitchell and was later covered by Crosby, Stills, Nash & Young?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Woodstock", "incorrectAnswers": ["Our House", "Carry On", "Always Cut My Hair"]}, {"question": "Gaborone is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Botswana", "incorrectAnswers": ["Lesotho", "Eswatini", "Malawi"]}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "W. K. Clifford", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "Friedrich Nietzsche", "Aristoteles"]}, {"question": "Which film contains the character 'Inspector Jacques Clouseau' ?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Pink Panther", "incorrectAnswers": ["Apocalypse Now", "Fargo", "The Treasure of the Sierra Madre"]}, {"question": "The language 'Hindi' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Indo-European", "incorrectAnswers": ["Uralic", "Dravidian", "Austronesian"]}, {"question": "'Finding Nemo' was released in which year?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "2003", "incorrectAnswers": ["1997", "2000", "2006"]}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Robert Louis Stevenson", "incorrectAnswers": ["Agatha Christie", "Joseph Conrad", "Oscar Wilde"]}, {"question": "Who wrote 'The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Douglas Adams", "incorrectAnswers": ["Stephen King", "Terry Pratchett", "John Grisham"]}, {"question": "The language 'Hausa' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Afroasiatic", "incorrectAnswers": ["Austronesian", "Dravidian", "Niger-Congo"]}, {"question": "How are domestic canines more commonly known?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Dogs", "incorrectAnswers": ["Foxes", "Wolves", "Cows"]}, {"question": "Golden Earring had which hit single in 1973?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Radar Love", "incorrectAnswers": ["Long Blond Animal", "Eight Miles High", "No For An Answer"]}, {"question": "In which year was the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" released?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "1967", "incorrectAnswers": ["1965", "1966", "1968"]}, {"question": "What is phonetics concerned with?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Sounds", "incorrectAnswers": ["Grammar", "Meaning", "Writing"]}, {"question": "Who was considered the 'Father of Linguistics', a Swiss guy, who authored the seminal book entitled 'Course in General Linguistics' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Ferdinand de Saussure", "incorrectAnswers": ["William James", "Noam Chomsky", "Leonard Bloomfield"]}, {"question": "What animals can breathe \"with their cheeks\" ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Amphibians", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mammals", "Insects", "Birds"]}, {"question": "Arabic belongs to the ...", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Semitic languages", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nubian languages", "Berber languages", "Turkic languages"]}, {"question": "What is the derivative of f(x)=sin(x) ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "cos(x)", "incorrectAnswers": ["-cos(x)", "tan(x)", "cot(x)"]}, {"question": "Which is a synonym of 'penitent' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "contrite", "incorrectAnswers": ["diffident", "candent", "impolite"]}, {"question": "What can be a possible cause for packet loss in the Internet ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Network congestion", "incorrectAnswers": ["Checksum is in binary", "Phishing attack", "Receive window too large"]}, {"question": "What is the largest species of shark?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Whale Shark", "incorrectAnswers": ["Great White Shark", "Hammerhead Shark", "Tiger Shark"]}, {"question": "Which animal is known for its ability to change color to blend into its surroundings?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Chameleon", "incorrectAnswers": ["Octopus", "Flamingo", "Peacock"]}, {"question": "What is the primary defense mechanism of a skunk?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Spraying a foul-smelling liquid", "incorrectAnswers": ["Camouflage", "Loud screeching", "Playing dead"]}, {"question": "How many species of skunks are there?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "12", "incorrectAnswers": ["2", "4", "10"]}, {"question": "What does \"CPU\" stand for in computer terminology?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Central Processing Unit", "incorrectAnswers": ["Control Program Utility", "Central Power Unit", "Computer Personal Unit"]}, {"question": "Which programming language is primarily used for web development on the client side?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "JavaScript", "incorrectAnswers": ["Java", "C++", "Python"]}, {"question": "In computer networking, what does the term \"latency\" refer to?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The time it takes for data to travel from the source to the destination", "incorrectAnswers": ["The amount of data transmitted over a network", "The maximum bandwidth available in a network", "The number of devices connected to a network"]}, {"question": "Which significant historical event took place in Augsburg in 1555?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Augsburg Peace of Religion", "incorrectAnswers": ["The signing of the Treaty of Augsburg", "The establishment of the Augsburg Confession", " The beginning of the Thirty Years' War"]}, {"question": "What is the value of the derivative of the function  \ud835\udc53 ( \ud835\udc65 ) = 3 \ud835\udc65 2 \u2212 5 \ud835\udc65 + 4 f(x)=3x  2  \u22125x+4 at the point  \ud835\udc65 = 2 x=2?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "7", "incorrectAnswers": ["1", "5", "10"]}, {"question": "What is the fundamental theorem of algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n roots in the complex number system.", "incorrectAnswers": ["Every polynomial can be factored into linear factors.", "The sum of the angles in a triangle is 180 degrees. ", "The product of the roots of a polynomial is equal to the constant term."]}, {"question": "What is the profession of the character Sean Maguire, played by Robin Williams, in Good Will Hunting?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Psychologist", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mathematician", "Professor", "Carpenter"]}, {"question": "What is the primary focus of the film My Own Private Idaho?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The journey of two friends who are also hustlers.", "incorrectAnswers": ["The life of a successful businessman.", "A family's struggle with mental illness.", "A road trip across America for a music festival."]}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Alejandro Gonz\u00e1lez I\u00f1\u00e1rritu?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "All of the above", "incorrectAnswers": ["Birdman", "The Revenant", "Babel"]}, {"question": "What major event took place in Algeria from 1954 to 1962?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Algerian War of Independenc", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Algerian Civil War", "The establishment of the Algerian Republic", "The Battle of Algiers"]}, {"question": "What language family does Tigrinya belong to?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Afro-Asiatic", "incorrectAnswers": ["Indo-European", "Niger-Congo", "Sino-Tibetan"]}, {"question": "What was the significance of the Battle of Adwa in 1896 for Ethiopia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "It secured Ethiopian sovereignty against Italian invasion.", "incorrectAnswers": ["It marked the end of the Ethiopian Civil War.", " It was the first time Ethiopia was colonized.", " It led to the establishment of the Ethiopian Empire."]}, {"question": "What was the title of King Crimson's debut album released in 1969?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "In the Court of the Crimson King", "incorrectAnswers": ["Red", "Discipline", "Larks' Tongues in Aspic"]}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is considered David Foster Wallace's magnum opus?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Infinite Jest", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Broom of the System", "Girl with Curious Hair", "Brief Interviews with Hideous Men"]}, {"question": "Which prestigious award did Elfriede Jelinek receive in 2004?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Nobel Prize in Literature", "incorrectAnswers": ["Booker Prize", "Goethe Prize", "Pulitzer Prize"]}, {"question": "What was the significance of Ravenna during the Roman Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "It was the capital of the Western Roman Empire.", "incorrectAnswers": ["It was the birthplace of Julius Caesar. ", "It was the location of the Colosseum.", "It served as the main naval base of the Roman fleet."]}, {"question": "Which of the following philosophers is most commonly associated with existentialism?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Jean-Paul Sartre", "incorrectAnswers": ["Karl Marx", "Immanuel Kant", "Friedrich Nietzsche"]}, {"question": "What is Gottlob Frege primarily known for in the field of philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Founding modern logic and philosophy of language", "incorrectAnswers": ["Developing the theory of relativity", "Establishing the concept of the unconscious", "Introducing existentialism"]}, {"question": "Which concept is most closely associated with Horkheimer and Adorno in their critique of culture and society?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The \"Culture Industry\"", "incorrectAnswers": ["The \"Social Contract\"", "Pragmatism", "Crisis of Meaning"]}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Rousseau's work The Social Contract?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The importance of individual freedom and the general will", "incorrectAnswers": ["The necessity of absolute monarchy", "The inevitability of social inequality", "The rejection of private property"]}, {"question": "What is the primary diet of raccoons (Procyon lotor)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Omnivorous, eating both plant and animal matter", "incorrectAnswers": ["Carnivorous, primarily feeding on other animals", "Herbivorous, primarily feeding on plants", "Insectivorous, primarily feeding on insects"]}, {"question": "What is a unique reproductive feature of seahorses (Hippocampus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "The males carry and incubate the eggs in a pouch.", "incorrectAnswers": ["They lay eggs in a nest.", "They reproduce asexually. ", "They have a symbiotic relationship with other fish for reproduction."]}, {"question": "What is one of the most distinctive social behaviors of bonobos (Pan paniscus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "They use sexual behavior to resolve conflicts and strengthen social bonds.", "incorrectAnswers": ["They primarily use tools for foraging. ", "They exhibit strong male dominance hierarchies.", "They are strictly solitary animals."]}, {"question": "What major event occurred in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in 1960?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Congo Crisis and the declaration of independence from Belgium", "incorrectAnswers": ["The establishment of Belgian colonial rule", "The rise of Mobutu Sese Seko to power", "The first democratic elections"]}, {"question": "Which of the following works is written by Dimitri Verhulst?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "The Misfortunates", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Sorrow of Belgium", "The Book of Chameleons", "The Discovery of Heaven"]}, {"question": "What is the primary reason for the hibernation of dormice (Gliridae), commonly known as \"Siebenschl\u00e4fer\"?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "To survive food scarcity during winter", "incorrectAnswers": ["To avoid predators", "To migrate to warmer climates", "To enter a mating period"]}, {"question": "Which of the following mechanisms do Venus flytraps (Dionaea muscipula) use to capture their prey?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Snap trapping", "incorrectAnswers": ["Passive trapping", "Pitfall trapping", "Adhesive trapping"]}, {"question": "Which novel is J.D. Salinger best known for, featuring the character Holden Caulfield?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "incorrectAnswers": ["Franny and Zooey", "Nine Stories", "Raise High the Roof Beam, Carpenter"]}, {"question": "What is the scientific name for the giant sequoia, commonly known as the mammoth tree?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Sequoiadendron giganteum", "incorrectAnswers": ["Sequoia sempervirens", "Taxodium distichum", "Metasequoia glyptostroboides"]}, {"question": "Which of the following novels was written by Clemens J. Setz?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Indigo", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Invention of Morel", "The Hour of the Star", "The Floating Theatre"]}, {"question": "What is the primary purpose of eigenvalues and eigenvectors in linear algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "To analyze linear transformations and their effects on vector spaces", "incorrectAnswers": ["To solve systems of equations", "To determine the rank of a matrix", "To calculate the determinant of a matrix"]}, {"question": "Which of the following distributions is characterized by its bell-shaped curve and is commonly used in statistics?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Normal distribution", "incorrectAnswers": ["Poisson distribution", "Exponential distribution", "Binomial distribution"]}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is written by Tahar Ben Jelloun?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "This Blinding Absence of Light", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Sand Child", "The Invisible Man", "The Name of the Rose"]}, {"question": "Which of the following authors is known for their significant contributions to Maghrebian literature?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Assia Djebar", "incorrectAnswers": ["Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez", "Naguib Mahfouz", "Mario Vargas Llosa"]}, {"question": "When was Heidelberg University founded?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "1386", "incorrectAnswers": ["1453", "1600", "1750"]}, {"question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"Heidelberg\" and visited the city several times in the 19th century?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Mark Twain", "incorrectAnswers": ["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Friedrich Schiller", "Heinrich Heine"]}, {"question": "In which movie did Matt Damon portray an astronaut stranded on Mars?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Martian", "incorrectAnswers": ["Interstellar", "Gravity", "Elysium"]}, {"question": "What is the name of the famous street depicted in Fellini's La Dolce Vita?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Via Veneto", "incorrectAnswers": ["Via Condotti", "Via Appia", "Via del Corso"]}, {"question": "Which of the following films is a political satire directed by Nanni Moretti?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Il Caimano", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mia Madre", "Caro Diario", "La Messa \u00e8 Finita"]}, {"question": "Zabriskie Point is famous for its final sequence. What happens during this scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "A house explodes in slow motion", "incorrectAnswers": ["A protest turns violent", "A car chase through the desert", "The protagonists escape to Mexico"]}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Ken Park?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Teenage alienation and dysfunctional families", "incorrectAnswers": ["Urban crime and corruption", "Drug addiction and recovery", "Political activism and rebellion"]}, {"question": "Which character is an undercover cop infiltrating the Irish mob in The Departed?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Billy Costigan", "incorrectAnswers": ["Colin Sullivan", "Frank Costello", "Sean Dignam"]}, {"question": "What is the meaning of the standard deviation in a dataset?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The measure of the spread or dispersion of the data", "incorrectAnswers": ["The average of the data points", "The range of the dataset", "The square of the mean"]}, {"question": "What is the determinant of a square matrix used to determine?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Whether the matrix is invertible", "incorrectAnswers": ["The trace of the matrix", "The rank of the matrix", "The eigenvalues of the matrix"]}, {"question": "What is the main focus of Wittgenstein's early work, Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Language and its relation to reality", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ethics and morality", "The nature of time", "The existence of God"]}, {"question": "What is the primary concern of linguistic philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The relationship between language, thought, and reality", "incorrectAnswers": ["The study of phonetics and grammar", "The history of language development", "The classification of languages"]}, {"question": "What is Giambattista Vico's view on the nature of human history?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "History is cyclical and characterized by recurring themes and patterns", "incorrectAnswers": ["History is linear and progresses towards a specific goal", "History is completely random and lacks any discernible order", "History is solely determined by economic factors"]}, {"question": "Which philosopher proposed the idea that history is a struggle between the ruling class and the oppressed class?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Karl Marx", "incorrectAnswers": ["Alexis de Tocqueville", "Max Weber", "Michel Foucault"]}, {"question": "What significant event occurred in 711 AD that impacted the history of Andalusia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The arrival of the Moors and the beginning of Muslim rule", "incorrectAnswers": ["The establishment of the Spanish Inquisition", "The Reconquista", "The discovery of America"]}, {"question": "Which event in 1979 dramatically changed the political landscape of Iran?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Islamic Revolution", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Anglo-Persian War", "The Constitutional Revolution", "The Iran-Iraq War"]}, {"question": "What was the Aksum Empire primarily known for?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Its advanced agricultural techniques and trade networks", "incorrectAnswers": ["Its naval power and exploration", "Its conquests of neighboring territories", "Its vast collection of written literature"]}, {"question": "Which of the following empires is associated with the rise of Timbuktu as a prominent city?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Mali Empire", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Roman Empire", "The Ottoman Empire", "The Byzantine Empire"]}, {"question": "Timbuktu is located in which present-day country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Mali", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nigeria", "Senegal", "Burkina Faso"]}, {"question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Constantinople", "incorrectAnswers": ["Rome", "Athens", "Alexandria"]}, {"question": "What is a neural network?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "A computational model inspired by the way biological neural networks in the human brain process information", "incorrectAnswers": ["A type of computer virus", "A hardware component of a computer", "A network of interconnected computers"]}, {"question": "Which novel is based on Thomas Mann's own family background and examines the decline of a wealthy merchant family?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Buddenbrooks", "incorrectAnswers": ["Confessions of Felix Krull", "The Magic Mountain", "The Holy Sinner"]}, {"question": "In which city was Goethe born?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Frankfurt am Main", "incorrectAnswers": ["Weimar", "Berlin", "Stuttgart"]}, {"question": "Sloths are known for their slow metabolism. Approximately how long can it take for a sloth to digest food?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "30-40 hours", "incorrectAnswers": ["12-24 hours", "1-2 weeks", "2-3 hours"]}, {"question": "What family do dogs, wolves, and foxes belong to?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Canidae", "incorrectAnswers": ["Felidae", "Mustelidae", "Ursidae"]}, {"question": "Domestic pigs are known for their intelligence. Which of the following animals are they often compared to in terms of cognitive abilities?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Dogs", "incorrectAnswers": ["Cats", "Cows", "Horses"]}, {"question": "What does \"open\" software mean?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Software whose source code is available for modification and distribution", "incorrectAnswers": ["Software that is free of charge", "Software that is only available online", "Software that requires a license"]}, {"question": "Which sorting algorithm is known for its efficiency in large datasets and is commonly implemented in many programming languages?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Quick Sort", "incorrectAnswers": ["Selection Sort", "Bubble Sort", "Insertion Sort"]}, {"question": "Which of the following is a fundamental data structure in computer science used to store a collection of items?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "All of the above", "incorrectAnswers": ["Array", "Graph", "Tree"]}, {"question": "Which philosophical tradition is Hegel associated with?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Idealism", "incorrectAnswers": ["Empiricism", "Existentialism", "Rationalism"]}, {"question": "What is the title of Spinoza's most significant work, where he presents his philosophical ideas on God, nature, and ethics?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Ethics", "incorrectAnswers": ["Theological-Political Treatise", "Tractatus Politicus", "Axioms of Religion"]}, {"question": "Meister Eckhart was a prominent figure in which philosophical and theological tradition?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Christian Mysticism", "incorrectAnswers": ["Sufism", "Rationalism", "Scholasticism"]}, {"question": "What is the definition of a limit in the context of calculus?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The value that a function approaches as the input approaches a certain point.", "incorrectAnswers": ["The highest value of a function.", "The rate of change of a function. ", "The area under a curve."]}, {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a normal distribution?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "It has a mean, median, and mode that are all equal.", "incorrectAnswers": ["It is uniform.", "It has two peaks.", "It is skewed to the right."]}, {"question": "In calculus, what does the derivative of a function represent?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The instantaneous rate of change of the function.", "incorrectAnswers": ["The area under the curve of the function.", "The average rate of change of the function.", "The maximum value of the function."]}, {"question": "Which of the following is one of Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns's most famous works?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Carnival of the Animals", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Rite of Spring", "The Four Seasons", "The Nutcracker Suite"]}, {"question": "Which instrument did John Coltrane play?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Saxophone", "incorrectAnswers": ["Trumpet", "Trombone", "Piano"]}, {"question": "Holst composed \"The Planets\" between 1914 and 1917. How many movements are in this suite?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "7", "incorrectAnswers": ["5", "8", "9"]}, {"question": "In which film did Woody Allen win an Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Annie Hall", "incorrectAnswers": ["Match Point", "Hannah and Her Sisters", "Crimes and Misdemeanors"]}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Pedro Almod\u00f3var?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Talk to Her", "incorrectAnswers": ["Pan's Labyrinth", "Am\u00e9lie", "The Sea Inside"]}, {"question": "Which of the following films directed by Herzog features a narrative about the construction of an opera house in the Amazon rainforest?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Fitzcarraldo", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nosferatu", "Stroszek", "My Best Fiend"]}, {"question": "Thomas Bernhard often criticized which aspect of Austrian culture in his writings?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Nationalism and conformity", "incorrectAnswers": ["The arts", "The education system", "Environmental issues"]}, {"question": "What is the title of Hemingway's novella that tells the story of an old fisherman and his struggle with a giant marlin?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "The Old Man and the Sea", "incorrectAnswers": ["Islands in the Stream", "A Moveable Feast", "The Snows of Kilimanjaro"]}, {"question": "What is the study of the rules governing the structure of sentences in a language called?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Syntax", "incorrectAnswers": ["Semantics", "Pragmatics", "Morphology"]}, {"question": "In phonetics, what is the term for the smallest unit of sound that can distinguish meaning in a language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Phoneme", "incorrectAnswers": ["Morpheme", "Grapheme", "Allophone"]}, {"question": "Which theory posits that the structure of a language influences its speakers' worldview or cognition?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Relativity Hypothesis (Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis)", "incorrectAnswers": ["Universal Grammar", "Structuralism", "Generative Grammar"]}, {"question": "What is the approximate length of the Niger River, making it one of the longest rivers in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "4200 kilometers", "incorrectAnswers": ["1600 kilometers", "2600 kilometers", "5800 kilometers"]}, {"question": "The Danube Delta, a UNESCO World Heritage site, is located in which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Romania", "incorrectAnswers": ["Bulgaria", "Hungary", "Serbia"]}, {"question": "Which of the following countries shares a border with Niger?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "All of the above", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nigeria", "Algeria", "Mali"]}, {"question": "Which city, known as a center of learning and trade, was part of the Mali Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Timbuktu", "incorrectAnswers": ["Cairo", "Lagos", "Marrakech"]}, {"question": "What was the primary military tactic used by the Mongol armies that contributed to their success?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Fast cavalry and mobility", "incorrectAnswers": ["Naval warfare", "Guerrilla warfare", "Siege warfare"]}, {"question": "Which of the following cat breeds is known for being hairless?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Sphynx", "incorrectAnswers": ["Maine Coon", "Siamese", "Persian"]}, {"question": "Which of these North American animals is known for its role in shaping river ecosystems by building dams?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "North American Beaver", "incorrectAnswers": ["Grizzly Bear", "American Bison", "Gray Wolf"]}, {"question": "In the context of database management, what does the acronym ACID stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability", "incorrectAnswers": ["Availability, Concurrency, Integrity, Deletion", "Authorization, Compression, Inference, Distribution", "Asynchronous, Centralized, Inverse, Denormalized"]}, {"question": "Which algorithmic paradigm does the Dijkstra's algorithm for shortest paths primarily rely on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Greedy Algorithm", "incorrectAnswers": ["Dynamic Programming", "Divide and Conquer", "Backtracking"]}, {"question": "Which is the longest mountain range in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Atlas Mountains", "incorrectAnswers": ["Simien Mountains", "Rwenzori Mountains", "Drakensberg Mountains"]}, {"question": "What is the world highest mountain?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Mount Everest", "incorrectAnswers": ["Denali", "K2", "Kilimanjaro"]}, {"question": "Which empire was known for its extensive trade networks and cultural exchanges during the early modern period in India?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Mughal Empire", "incorrectAnswers": ["Gupta Empire", "Maurya Empire", "Chola Dynasty"]}, {"question": "Which civilization is known for its advanced architectural achievements and the creation of the calendar, and was prominent in Mexico before the Spanish conquest?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Maya", "incorrectAnswers": ["Olmec", "Aztec", "Inca"]}, {"question": "Which of the following language families includes languages such as Russian, Polish, and Czech?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Slavic", "incorrectAnswers": ["Romance", "Germanic", "Semitic"]}, {"question": "What is the primary characteristic that defines a language as belonging to the Sino-Tibetan language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "It is tonal and primarily spoken in East Asia.", "incorrectAnswers": ["It uses an alphabetic writing system.", " It includes only languages spoken in China.", "It has no grammatical structure."]}, {"question": "Which theorem states that every continuous function on a closed interval attains its maximum and minimum values?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Extreme Value Theorem", "incorrectAnswers": ["Mean Value Theorem", "Intermediate Value Theorem", "Bolzano-Weierstrass Theorem"]}, {"question": "Which theorem provides a method for approximating the value of a function using its derivatives at a single point?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Taylor's Theorem", "incorrectAnswers": ["L'H\u00f4pital's Rule", "Fundamental Theorem of Calculus", "Pythagorean Theorem"]}, {"question": "What is the central theme of Pedro Almod\u00f3var's film \"Todo sobre mi madre\" (All About My Mother)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The complexities of motherhood and identity", "incorrectAnswers": ["The search of a lost child", "The impact of war on families", "The challenges of aging"]}, {"question": "Which Alfred Hitchcock film features a character named Marion Crane, who becomes the victim of a notorious shower scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Psycho", "incorrectAnswers": ["Vertigo", "North By Northwest", "Rear Window"]}, {"question": "What is a primary characteristic that distinguishes heavy metal music from hard rock?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Heavier guitar riffs and darker themes", "incorrectAnswers": ["Use of clean vocals", "Emphasis on melodic hooks", "Inclusion of acoustic instruments"]}, {"question": "Which Focus album, released in 1971, features the hit single \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Moving Waves", "incorrectAnswers": ["Focus III", "Hamburger Concerto", "Live at the Rainbow"]}, {"question": "Which philosopher is known for the statement \"I think, therefore I am\"?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Ren\u00e9 Descartes", "incorrectAnswers": ["Friedrich Nietzsche", "Immanuel Kant", "John Locke"]}, {"question": "Schelling primarily associated with, emphasizing the idea of nature as a dynamic and self-revealing process?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Philosophy of Nature", "incorrectAnswers": ["Absolute Idealism", "Transcendental Idealism", "Dialectical Materialism"]}, {"question": "What scientific suborder does the family Hyaenidae belong to ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Feliformia", "incorrectAnswers": ["Haplorhini", "Ciconiiformes", "Caniformia"]}, {"question": "What is the scientific name of the cheetah?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Acinonyx jubatus", "incorrectAnswers": ["Panthera onca", "Lynx rufus", "Felis catus"]}, {"question": "What bird is born with claws on its wing digits?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Hoatzin", "incorrectAnswers": ["Cormorant", "Cassowary", "Secretary bird"]}, {"question": "Which of these is not a layer in the OSI model for data communications?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Connection Layer", "incorrectAnswers": ["Physical Layer", "Transport Layer", "Application Layer"]}, {"question": "What port does HTTP run on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "80", "incorrectAnswers": ["23", "53", "443"]}, {"question": "What does the International System of Quantities refer 1024 bytes as?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Kibibyte", "incorrectAnswers": ["Kylobyte", "Kelobyte", "Kilobyte"]}, {"question": "Which of these is NOT a real tectonic plate?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Atlantic Plate", "incorrectAnswers": ["North American Plate", "Eurasian Plate", "Nazca Plate"]}, {"question": "What is the most populous Muslim-majority nation in 2010?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Indonesia", "incorrectAnswers": ["Saudi Arabia", "Iran", "Sudan"]}, {"question": "How many countries border Kyrgyzstan?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "4", "incorrectAnswers": ["1", "3", "6"]}, {"question": "The Second Boer War in 1899 was fought where?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "South Africa", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nepal", "Bulgaria", "Argentina"]}, {"question": "Which day did World War I begin?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "July 28", "incorrectAnswers": ["January 28", "April 28", "June 28"]}, {"question": "How many women joined the United States Armed Services during World War II?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "350000", "incorrectAnswers": ["100000", "250000", "500000"]}, {"question": "What is the approximate value of mathematical constant e?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "2.72", "incorrectAnswers": ["1.41", "1.62", "3.14"]}, {"question": "What is the smallest number that can be expressed as the sum of two positive cubes in two different ways?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "1729", "incorrectAnswers": ["91", "561", "4104"]}, {"question": "The decimal number 31 in hexadecimal would be what?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "1F", "incorrectAnswers": ["1B", "2E", "3D"]}, {"question": "In which African country was the 2006 film 'Blood Diamond' mostly set in?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Sierra Leone", "incorrectAnswers": ["Liberia", "Burkina Faso", "Central African Republic"]}, {"question": "What was the first feature-length computer-animated movie?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Toy Story", "incorrectAnswers": ["Tron", "Lion king", "101 Dalmatians"]}, {"question": "Who directed \"E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\" (1982)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Steven Spielberg", "incorrectAnswers": ["Stanley Kubrick", "James Cameron", "Tim Burton"]}, {"question": "Who was the guitarist in the band \"The Doors\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Robby Krieger", "incorrectAnswers": ["Jim Morrison", "Ray Manzarek", "John Densmore"]}, {"question": "What was the name of Pink Floyd's first studio album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Piper at the Gates of Dawn", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ummagumma", "More", "Atom Heart Mother"]}, {"question": "What was The Velvet Underground's first album called?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "The Velvet Underground & Nico", "incorrectAnswers": ["The Velvet Underground", "Loaded", "White Light-White Heat"]}, {"question": "Which author co-wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" alongside Karl Marx?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Friedrich Engels", "incorrectAnswers": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "Gottlob Frege", "Arthur Schopenhauer"]}, {"question": "The novel \"Of Mice And Men\" was written by what author?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "John Steinbeck", "incorrectAnswers": ["George Orwell", "Mark Twain", "Harper Lee"]}, {"question": "In the year 1818, novelist Mary Shelly is credited with writing a fiction novel and creating this infamous character.", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Frankenstein's monster", "incorrectAnswers": ["Dracula", "The Thing", "The Invisible Man"]}, {"question": "Who wrote the novel \"Moby Dick\"?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "correctAnswer": "Herman Melville", "incorrectAnswers": ["William Golding", "William Shakespeare", "J. R. R. Tolkien"]}, {"question": "Which concept is central to Schopenhauer's philosophy and is described as the driving force behind all life and phenomena?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Will", "incorrectAnswers": ["Reason", "Being", "Knowledge"]}, {"question": "In Thus Spoke Zarathustra, what concept does Nietzsche introduce as a model for personal growth, symbolizing an ideal of strength, creativity, and self-overcoming?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "\u00dcbermensch (Overman)", "incorrectAnswers": ["Eternal Recurrence", "Slave Morality", "Apollonian and Dionysian"]}, {"question": "Which of these languages does not use articles?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Turkish", "incorrectAnswers": ["Swahili", "Italian", "Arabic"]}, {"question": "What is the term for a speech sound produced without any significant constriction of the airflow in the vocal tract?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "correctAnswer": "Vowel", "incorrectAnswers": ["Fricative", "Plosive", "Affricate"]}, {"question": "In phonetics, which of the following describes a sound made by fully stopping the airflow and then releasing it, as in the sounds /p/ or /t/?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "correctAnswer": "Plosive", "incorrectAnswers": ["Nasal", "Lateral", "Approximant"]}]}
